

Portugal

+351 926 843 295

franciscoandre.farp@gmail.com

My Portfolio in ffarps.github.io

My linkedin

OBJECTIVE

My name is Francisco André Rodrigues Pereira, I'm 22 years old, from Mirandela, and I graduated from the Polytechnic Institute of Braganca with a degree in Informatics Engineering.

During the third year of the course and after completing it, I was awarded two research grants by the Centre for Research in Digitalisation and Intelligent Robotics (CeDRI).

Proactive and dedicated, ready to achieve great things.

EXPERIENCE

Fev 2024-Present Full Stack Developer Intern at GoTVee

Implementation of an AI virtual assistant, designed to interact with various documents and web pages, such as PDFs, CSVs, XMLs and Confluence. The assistant uses NLP and machine learning to answer questions about documents, increasing productivity and facilitating access to information. I supported the development of an API broker and engineered data to train language models. I also optimised the code base with cross-functional teams.

Jul 2023-Sep 2023 Research Fellowship at CeDRI

CeDRI, Instituto Politécnico de Bragança

Contributed to an OpenZDM project related to developing a C# and OpenGl-based tool in Unity 3D, that aims to reduce defects in production chains in a car factory in the assembly and body shop zones.

Jul 2022-Jan 2023 Research Fellowship at CeDRI

CeDRI, Instituto Politécnico de Bragança

Worked on developing Augmented Reality (AR) and Virtual Reality (VR) apps in Unity, using different frameworks and tools, such as MRTK, ARCore, Vuforia SDK and ARFoundation.

EDUCATION

Oct 2019-Jul 2023 **Degree in Informatics Engineering** Instituto Politécnico de Bragança

Scientific Areas: Computer Science, Computer Engineering, Mathematics, Information Systems. Worked on many projects related to Web Development, Computer Architecture, Networking, 3D Modeling, Machine Learning, Data Structures, SQL and IoT.

2016-2019 **High School Diploma** Agrupamento de Escolas de Mirandela

Science and technology

LANGUAGES

HARD SKILLS

Portuguese - native **English** - proficient **German** - rudimentary Programming: C#, Python, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, etc.

Source Control: Git, GitHub, GitLab, BitBucket

Linux and Bash

Unity 3D

Databases: SQL and NoSQL

SOFT SKILLS

Self-taught Attention to detail **Technical Writing** Teamwork

PUBLICATIONS

An Augmented Reality Intelligent Guide for the Automotive Industry University of Twente, Enschede, The Netherlands · Jul 11, 2024

Show publication

Conference paper on Learning Factories of the Future (CFL 2024)